Ang Wei Jie

Data Analyst

in linkedin.com/in/angweijie94



https://github.com/weiji3x

Tel: +65 9115 4310

Email: weiji3x@gmail.com

Address: Ang Mo Kio Ave 5

Singapore 560181

PROFILE

Data analyst with strong analytical and problem-solving skills that excels at identifying business requirements, identifying connections and trend from data sets to generate actionable insights to drive informed decision-making. Equipped with data visualization skills to convey these insights to relevant stakeholders to improve company decision-making. Experienced in project and people management with ability to manage projects and collaborate effectively with diverse teams.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

System Analyst, UOB (United Overseas Bank) September 2022 - November 2023

- Coordinated activities with engineering, infrastructure, security and product team for deployment of risk management web application.
- Worked with the data source team to ensure correct data is being cleaned, transformed, delivered and ingested into the application.
- Developed shell scripts for application operations which are scheduled and run through a scheduler (Control-M).
- Facilitated and participated in application testing in SIT, UAT with testing team and end users.
- Set up of user management configuration (function and accessibility of different types of users) for web application.

Development Engineer, A*STAR - ARTC (Advanced Remanufacturing & Technology Centre) August 2019 - June 2022

- Engaged in research with industry partners to address industry issues/gaps/needs for digital factory simulation and digital twin.
- Led project scoping with internal and external stakeholders to establish communication plans, built project schedules and established clear project deliverables and milestones.
- Executed and delivered technical projects/workstreams regarding digital factory simulation and digital twin.
- Designed and simulated digital factory in 3D simulation model.
- Analysed and optimised simulated production line.
- Created digital twin of live physical production line.

SKILLS

Data Analytics:

- Data Cleaning
- Data Manipulation
- **Predictive Modeling**

Data Visualization:

Tableau

Database:

- Oracle
- **PostgreSQL**

3D Simulation & Modeling:

- Siemens Tecnomatix
- Siemens NX
- Solidworks Emulate3D

Programming:

- Python
- Shell-scripting (Linux)

Microsoft (Words, Excel, PowerPoint)

Project Management

LANGUAGUES

- **English**
- Chinese

CERTIFICATIONS

User Experience Design Bootcamp (IBF-STS P210802XCG), Vertical Institute.

Attained in August 2022

Develop a Risk Management Implementation Plan (MF-COM-402E-1), ASRETEC PTE. LTD.

Attained in October 2020

Programme Management (ICT-PMT-3002-1.1), EPM Training Services PTE. LTD.

Attained in March 2020

PROJECTS

Influenza Death Analysis of United States

- Cleaned and analyze historical data from CDC dataset to identify trends in the Influenza outbreak in United States.
- Built Tableau dashboards to present trends found and recommended a staffing plan for the upcoming Influenza season.
- Applications used for project:
 - ✓ Excel
 - ✓ Tableau

Video & Customers Analysis of Video Rental Company

- Conducted an SQL data analysis on the company database to provide the management with insights on their current customer base.
- Performed data cleaning and data extraction from database using CTE and subqueries to group and gather required data for analysis.
- Generated visualization to present to stakeholders regarding their customer base and recommendations on how to improve their business strategies.
- Applications used for project:
 - ✓ Excel
 - ✓ Tableau
 - ✓ PostgreSQL

Consumer Behavior Analysis of Online Grocery Store

- Carried out an analysis on Instacart customer's dataset to extract insights on customers behaviors and sales pattern.
- Produced visualization to present to stakeholders to answer their question regarding customer behaviors and customer segmentations.
- Gave recommendations on how to improve their marketing and segmentation strategies.
- Application used for project:
 - ✓ Excel
 - ✓ Python

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Mechanical Engineering Nanyang Technological University, Singapore (Aug 2016 – Jun 2019)

GPA: 4.69/5.00

Graduated with First Class Honours

Diploma in Aerospace Technology with Minor in Business Management Ngee Ann Polytechnic, Singapore (Apr 2011 – May 2014)

GPA: 3.94/4.00

 Graduated with Merit (Top 10% of Cohort)